

Gustavo Rayos













575-520-5199

gustavorayos @outlook.com San Francisco Bay Area gustavorayos.com

@gustavorayos

@gustavorayos

Summary

Dedicated Computer Systems Engineer since 2015. Currently holds an <u>active DoD Secret Security Clearance</u> and is <u>CompTIA Security+ Certified</u>. Experienced in Information Systems Engineering, Systems Administration, Systems Automation and Deployment, and Cyber Security. Performs system configuration, deployment automation, workstation patching, vulnerability management, and system analysis. Received Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science from New Mexico State University in 2015.

Skills

LANGUAGES

TECHNOLOGIES

- Bash • Linux (RHEL) • Python SCAP STIGViewer • PowerShell DOS/Windows VMWare Java • Hyper-V JavaScript Ansible CSS NIS Server/Client • HTML Git
- Active DirectoryGroup PolicyWDS & MDTSCCM
- DNSDHCPTenableMacOS

Experience

SENIOR INFORMATION SYSTEMS ANALYST (DOD SECRET SECURITY CLEARANCE)

Lockheed Martin Space | Sunnyvale, CA | November 2020 – March 2023

- Designed and developed software to automate our Linux deployments for the Lockheed Martin THAAD
 Missile program.
- Developed Kickstart script/process to easily deploy Linux workstations and servers efficiently.
- Deployed and administered Ansible Configuration Management server on multiple networks.
- Deployed Tang services to automate the access of LUKs encrypted drives on the network.
- Designed test environment to test software, systems, and other deployments before production.
- Performed successful root cause analysis for problem resolution in Windows environments.
- Analyzed and assessed server performance, storage capacity and planning for future needs.
- Performed routine server/workstation patching per guidelines.
- Performed Cyber-security tasks such as apply system SCANs, STIGs, Controls, Policies, perform remediation develop POAMs, and support security audits.
- Successfully installed server and associated hardware.
- Successfully installed/configured software applications and programs.
- Created/edited Standard Operating Instructions (SOI) documentation.
- DoD Secret Security Clearance.

SYSTEMS ENGINEER (DOD SECRET SECURITY CLEARANCE)

Raytheon Missile Systems | Tucson, AZ | March 2019 - October 2020

- Developed software packages to automate our standard OS configuration on Test Equipment (TE).
- Deployed a Windows Deployment Server (WDS) and Microsoft Deployment Toolkit (MDT) server and was responsible for task sequence configuration and client system deployment.

- Configured Windows and RHEL operating system to STIG standards.
- Worked closely with Cyber Security attending meetings for TE software and hardware configuration.
- Attended Sigma Six discussions providing useful feedback as a member of a project team.
- Worked as a member of a system administration team responsible for Test Equipment (TE) computer systems.
- Participated in system design, security solutions, system imaging, data recovery, hardware diagnostics, and unique problem solutions in multiple heterogeneous network environments.
- Assisted with managing user accounts, network access, generation and maintenance of web-page content, infrastructure, database support, and system backups.
- Provided solutions to a variety of technical problems of moderate scope and complexity primarily with internal company contacts.
- Documented procedures for system operations.
- DoD Secret Security Clearance.

SYSTEMS ADMINISTRATOR (DOE Q SECURITY CLEARANCE)

CNS Pantex | Amarillo, TX | December 2015 - March 2019

- Attended weekly Vulnerability Assessment Management meetings and help responsibility for technical patching on Pantex systems. Security patching included Microsoft and 3rd party applications.
- Calculated Site Performance Review (SPR) monthly metrics, and reviewed system compliance on the Pantex network. Average monthly system compliance on the Pantex network was 99% compliant.
- Reviewed and approved non-standard security exceptions for individual users and systems.
- Developed security protocols and procedures using various tools including PowerShell scripts, SCCM, Group Policy, Active Directory, Tenable, Splunk, Citrix, and more.
- Created and configured standalone system media for government issued laptops which included Cisco AnyConnect VPN software.
- Acted as a direct contact for PeopleSoft, Java, Acrobat, Reader, Flash Player, and deployments.
- Acted as a direct contact for any VPN related issues.
- DoE Q Top Secret Security Clearance

HIGH-PERFORMANCE COMPUTING RESEARCHER

Los Alamos National Laboratory | Los Alamos, NM | May 2015 - August 2015

- Researched Ceph Object Storage Software.
- Built a Linux computer cluster of 11 nodes and configured DNS, DHCP, NTP, NFS, HTTP, Authentication and Authorization, Users and Groups, LDAP, and Kerberos.
- Conducted read and write tests on a computer cluster of 11 nodes. Increased performance of default configuration of Ceph object storage software by 11%.
- Contributed work to a team of 3 computer science interns.
- Presented findings to Los Alamos National Laboratory computer scientists.

Education

BACHELOR OF ARTS IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

New Mexico State University | Las Cruces, NM | January 2014 - December 2015

Followed my passion for computers and programming and excelled in Java and C programming courses, network security and architecture courses, and completed research on HPC systems and software. Minored in Software Development and Algorithms Theory. Graduated with a 3.5 GPA.

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN BIOLOGY

New Mexico State University | Las Cruces, NM | August 2007 - May 2013

Completed studies in Biology and continued on to work in an environmental laboratory. Minored in Biochemistry. Graduated with a 3.5 GPA.